Guide to the Franklin M. Foote Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Franklin Manley Foote papers
1935-1972
1959-1972
MS 848
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
(5 boxes)
Office files, printed matter, and press releases documenting Franklin M. Foote's service as commissioner of the Connecticut State Department of Health (1959-1972), as a member of the Connecticut Clean Air Commission and Air Pollution Control Program (1970-1971), and the Council on Tuberculosis. Included also are a small amount of papers from 1935 and 1936 of Dr. Stanley Hart Osborn who was then commissioner of the Department of Health. These papers form part of the Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection.
Foote, Franklin Manley, 1908-
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Franklin M. Foote, 1977-1978.
Biographical / Historical
Franklin M. Foote: public health physician; B.S., Yale, 1930, M.D., 1933, D.P.H., 1935; chief, division of local health administration, Connecticut State Dept. of Health, 1937-1941; district health officer, New York City, 1941-1946; medical director, later executive director, National Society for the Prevention of Blindness, 1946-1959; commissioner, Connecticut State Dept. of Health, 1959-1973; lecturer in public health and epidemiology, Yale, 1959-.
Arrangement
Series I. Papers of Dr. Franklin M. Foote, 1959-1972
Series II. Papers of Dr. Franklin M. Foote and Dr. Stanley Hart Osborn, 1935-1936; 1959-1971
Scope and Contents
The Franklin M. Foote Papers consist of Dr. Foote's files as Commissioner of the Connecticut State Department of Health. Included among the papers are files on state and local public health agencies, commissions, and services, 1959-1960; the Connecticut Clean Air Commission and Air Pollution Control Program, 1970-1971; the Council on Tuberculosis and Control, 1972; and press releases, 1962-1963. Also included are the papers of Dr. Stanley Hart Osborne who served as Commissioner in 1935-1936.
The papers were received from Dr. Franklin M. Foote in 1977.
Air -- Pollution; Pollution; Public health -- Connecticut; Physicians; Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection; Foote, Franklin Manley, 1908-; Osborn, Stanley Hart, 1924-; Connecticut. Clean Air Commission; Connecticut. Council on Tuberculosis; Connecticut. State Department of Health
- Papers of Dr. Franklin M. Foote, 1959-1972; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  From the period in which he was Commissioner of the Connecticut State Department of Health.
  - Administrative files on state and local agencies, commissions, and services related to public health, 1959, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Administrative files on state and local agencies, commissions, and services related to public health (continued), 1960 (Box 2)
  - News releases of the Connecticut State Department of Health, 1962-1963 (Box 2)
  - Files on the Council on Tuberculosis Control, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Files on the Connecticut Air Pollution Control Program, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Files on the Connecticut Clean Air Commission, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Verbatim proceedings of a public hearing on hospital costs before the Connecticut Council on Hospitals, 1971 March 26, April 2 (Box 3)
  - Findings of a Department of Health hearing on the Seaside Regional Center, 1972 (Box 3)
- Papers of Dr. Franklin M. Foote and Dr. Stanley Hart Osborn, 1935-1936; 1959-1971; Series II
  Note: The Administrative files of Dr. Franklin M. Foote were organized by subject. The Administrative files of Dr. Stanley Hart Osborn were kept according to a numerical filing system and were reorganized yearly. Only parts of his files for 1935 and 1936 appear in this accession.
  - Administrative files of Dr. Foote from his office as Connecticut State Department of Health Commissioner
    - Camps, 1969-1971 (Box 4)
    - Child Day Care, 1971 (Box 4)
    - Civil Defense, 1971 (Box 4)
    - Comprehensive Health Planning (Some folders are marked PL-89-749. Material relates to the Advisory Council for Comprehensive Health Planning and the many commissions under the Council.), 1969-1971 (Box 4)
    - Conference of Local Directors of Health and Connecticut State Department of Health, 1959-1968 (Box 4)
    - Connecticut Health League, 1961-1972 (Box 4)
    - Drug Advisory Council, 1969-1971 (Box 4)
    - Encephalitis Virus, 1968 (Box 4)
    - Exempt Narcotics, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
    - Hopsital Licensing, 1962-1968 (Box 4)
    - Pharmacy Inspection, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Files of Dr. Foote (continued)
    - Pharmacy Inspection, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Vermin Control, 1967-1970 (Box 5)
    - Water Pollution, 1962-1963 (Box 5)
  - Administrative Files of Dr. Stanley Hart Osborn, Commissioner, Connecticut State Department of Health, 1922-?.
    - 83A Public Health Council, 1935 (Box 5)
    - 86A Radio Talks, 1935 (Box 5)
    - 90A Rockefeller Foundation, 1935 (Box 5)
    - 92A State - Attorney General, 1935 (Box 5)
    - 95A State - Control (State Comptroller), 1935 (Box 5)
    - 102A State - Finance and Conrol (Board of), 1935 (Box 5)
    - 103A State - Fish and Game, 1935 (Box 5)
    - 104A State - Governor, 1935 (Box 5)
    - 113A State - Planning Board, 1935 (Box 5)
    - 114A State - Police, 1935 (Box 5)
    - 145A Tumor Committee Circular Letter, 1935 (Box 5)
    - 145A Tumor Committee, 1935 (Box 5)
    - 146A Tri-State Treaty Commission, 1935 (Box 5)
    - 150A U.S. - Children (Children's Bureau, U.S. Department of Labor), 1935 (Box 5)
    - 156A U.S. - Public Health Service, 1935 (Box 5)
    - 157A U.S. - Senate and House of Representatives, 1935 (Box 5)
    - 88A Personal SHO, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 89A Peronnel, Accidents, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 89A Personnel, Applications, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 91A Physiotherapy, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 96A Public Health Council, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 98A Publicity - Radio Talks - Lectures, etc. by People Outside of the Department, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 99A Questionnaires, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 100A Radio Talks - Talks - Lectures, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 104A Rockefeller Foundation, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 109A State - Control (Comptroller), 1936 (Box 5)
    - 110A State - Hairdresser and Cosmeticians, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 111A State - Dairy and Food, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 114A State - Education, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 118A State - Financial and Control, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 119A State - Fish and Game, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 120A State - Governor, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 128A State - Planning Board, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 129A State - Police, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 131A State - Public Welfare, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 133A State - Superintendent, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 140A State and Provincial Health Authorities, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - 143A Thermometers under 95 percent, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 145A Thermometers - Eisele Company, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 161A Tumor Committee Circular Letters, 1936 (Box 5)
    - 161A Tumor Committee, 1936 (Box 5)